本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Do you think the Eternal Well grants
insects power without a price?
常世の井戸が何の代償も無く蟲に力を与えると思うのか
They say it takes memories.
常世の井戸は与える力によってその記憶を奪っていくと言う
And the greater the power it bestows,
the more it will take...
姫君が全ての力を取り戻せば
Should the princess regain her entire power,
すなわち　全ての記憶を失うのだ
she will lose all of her memories!
H-Her memories will disappear?
お　お付きの方の記憶が　無くなる
The Promise Is Hope
Within Despair
What did you mean when you said that
she will lose all her memories?!
お付きの方が全ての記憶を無くすとは
どういう事だ
You climbed out of the Eternal Well,
from which no one may return alive?
人は生きては帰ることができぬ常世の井戸から這い出して来るとはな
貴様　ただの小鼠ではないな
You are no mere rat.
どういう事だ
What did you mean?
言葉通り　記憶を無くすとは全て忘れると言う事だ
Exactly what I said.
She will lose her memories,
and forget everything.
お前の事も　欠片も覚えてはおらぬだろうよ
She won't remember a thing about you.
自分の事はどうでもいい
I don't matter...
楽しかった事　嬉しかった事も　忘れると言うのか
But you're saying that she'll forget
the fun and happiness she had?!
阿呆やのう　親切に教えてやったと言うに
You are quite stupid.
I'm giving you a very simple explanation,
その言葉も分からぬか
but you still cannot understand?
な　何をするつもりだ
What are you doing?
もちろん　お付きの方をお救いします
I'm going to save the servant, of course!
She can't forget all the fun she had...
楽しかった事まで忘れるなど 許してはならないのです
I will not allow that to happen!
遅い　もはや間に合わぬ
It's too late...
You are too late.
せっかく拾った命　自分から捨てに行くとは
He was fortunate enough to survive,
and then he threw his life away.
度し難い阿呆よ
What a fool.
確かに愚か
Indeed, he is a fool...
But I, Tokugawa Munenao,
だが　あの者を笑う事は　この徳川宗直が許せぬ
shall not allow you to laugh at him!
Stop your squeaking, rat.
鼠がチューチューとうるさいな
面白い
Interesting.
人にもまだこのような戦の風をまとう者がいたか
So there are still humans who carry
the winds of battle with them?
Tsukishima, it was fun.
月島　楽しかったぞ
月島
Tsukishima!
お付きの方
Miss!
What are you doing?!
何をする
You can't stay here!
ここにいては駄目です
力を取り戻す代わりに
In exchange for restoring your power,
you'll lose all of your memories!
お付きの方の記憶は全て失われてしまうのです
妾の記憶が　無くなる
My memories will disappear?
月島との記憶が　無くなってしまうのか
I'll lose my memories of Tsukishima?
Of all the fun we had?
あの楽しかった記憶が　全て
お主との記憶を持って　 この先も生き続けようと誓ったと言うのに
I swore that I would live on,
with the memories you gave me...
さ　早くこの井戸から出ましょう
Now, let's get out of this Well!
何を言う
What are you saying?
妾が力を取り戻さねば　幸村を倒せぬのだぞ
If I cannot regain my power, we won't
be able to defeat Yukimura!
なんの　あれしきのムシケラ
Don't worry...
I can squash that insect without your power!
お付きの方の力を借りなくても
自分が踏み潰してみせます
どうしたのじゃ　月島
What's wrong, Tsukishima?
まさか　妾の毒か
It can't be... My poison?
なんの　これしき
This is nothing...
さ　行きましょう
Now, let's go.
お勤めとは言え
You can't forget the fun
and happiness you had,
そのために　嬉しかった事　楽しかった事を　忘れていいはずがありません
not even for the sake of duty...
あってはならないのです
You just can't!
Leave Yukimura to me.
幸村の事は　自分にお任せください
Believe in me, Tsukishima Jinbei... Miss!
この月島仁兵衛を信じてください　お付きの方
Let's go, Jinbei.
参ろう　仁兵衛
Get out of here while you can!
今のうちに早く逃げろー
You're mine!
打ち取ったリー
そうはいくかよ
Not happening!
Too slow.
遅い
What is this?
なんだこりゃ
苦しい
I can't breathe...
拙者の屁より臭いぞ
It smells worse than a fart.
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
末吉　為吉
全力突っ張りー
Full-Power Slap!
一旦引け
Fall back for now.
You don't need to tell me...
I can't take this.
言われなくても　これはたまらん
僕達には煙いだけだけど
To us, it merely smells like smoke.
あいつらは相当嫌みたいだな
But I guess they don't like it.
Could this be the Chinpou-style Insect Repellent?
もしかして　珍宝流の虫除け
あー　言った言った　珍宝流って言った
Hey, she said it...
She said "Chinpou-style."
うっさい
Shut up!
Onee-sama!
お姉様
I'm glad you're okay...
よくぞご無事で　いろり嬉しいのです
I'm so happy!
やっぱり
I knew it.
そうなのです
That's right...
秘伝　虫蒸し煙です
It's our clan's secret Bug-Blasting Smoke.
Chinpou-style:
Bug-Blasting Smoke
Chinpou-style Bug-Blasting Smoke!
珍宝流　虫蒸し煙
さすが我が珍宝流
Chinpou-style is so great—
Stop saying that!
それはいいから
でも　手筈通りやってくれたのね
But you followed the plan precisely, right?
はいです 町の人はほとんど避難しているです
Of course.
Most of the city has evacuated.
後少しで全ての避難は終わります
The rest will soon be out.
So, you got any more of
this bug-blaster stuff?
んで　その虫蒸しなんとかってまだあるのか
はい　あちらに
Yes... Over there.
Time to strike back.
反撃開始
貰ったー
You're mine.
さて　姫は何処へ行かれたかな
Now, then...
Where did the princess go?
くそうでくそうでかなわぬ
It just stinks so much.
たっぷりあるぜ
There's more where that came from!
今よ
Now!
僕は出来る子
I can do it!
How're you liking the smoke?
どうだ　煙の味は
How do you like my farts?
拙者のすかしっての味はいかがか
匂いは薄いが風圧最高
They don't smell too bad,
but they make a big blast!
貴様らの虫除けの煙など　一発で吹き飛ばしてくれる
They'll blow away your Insect Repellent!
There...
それ
Oh, crap.
やっべ
殺しはしない
I won't kill you.
すごい
Wow...
衝撃波を切り裂いた
He cut the blast wave in half.
Go quickly.
早く行け
Right!
承知
楽しいな　生きていると言う事は
Being alive is amusing...
浮かれている場合か
Is this the time for amusement?
一度死んだ身　生きる事の素晴らしさを噛み締めているのだ
I have died once.
I know full well how wonderful living is.
殿　奈阿姫様
My lord! Princess Naa!
殿　殿
My lord! My lord!
この幸村がおりながら　殿に毒を煽がせるとは
I, Yukimura, failed to protect
you from this poison...
姫は　奈阿姫様は何処に
Princess Naa...
Where is Princess Naa?
姫はご無事なのか
Is she all right?
You would save me?
助けるだと
不遜　不遜だぞ　ムシケラのくせに
H-How dare you even try, insect?
I do not require an ugly insect's assistance.
醜い蟲ごときの助けなどいらぬ
I, Yukimura, shall not die from this...
これしきの事で　この幸村
Stop...
止めよう　我が心の内に手を伸ばすな
Stay out of my heart.
I refuse to be a mere insect's servant!
ならんぞ　蟲ごときの手下などに
Stop!
止めよ　俺は豊臣の
I serve Lord Toyotomi...
It was a foolish loyalty.
くだらぬ忠義であった
死ぬよりは生き続ける事のほうが　どれ程大事であったか 今なら分かる
I now know how much more
important it is to live than die.
お前はもはや　戦国の勇　真田幸村ではない
You are no longer Sanada Yukimura,
the hero of the civil wars!
No, I am Yukimura.
いや　幸村だ
身も心もな
In body and soul.
我が主　常世の蟲も奈阿姫様を蘇らせるのに力を使い果たしていた
My lord,
the Insect of the Eternal Land,
used all its power reviving Princess Naa.
俺を蟲人の蛹にするのがやっと
Making me an Insect-man was all it could do.
そして　そこから羽化するのに百年使こうたわ
And it took a century for me
to emerge from my cocoon.
This time, you will sleep forever!
今度こそ眠りに付け
Interesting.
面白い
人とは面白い
Humans are so interesting...
たとえネズミでもな
Even rats!
お前なら　よき蟲人となれようぞ
You will make a splendid Insect-man.
Insect-man!
蟲人よ
This comes from our ancestors!
ご先祖様より受け継いだ紀州流築城術奥義
Kishuu-style Castle Construction,
Secret Technique: Avalanche!
岩雪崩れ
とくと食らうがいい
Here it comes!
どうだ　わが奥義
Well? Did my secret technique...
Rat...
ネズミよ　所詮お前らはつまらぬネズミ
You are nothing but boring rats, all of you.
Now, I tire of this.
さて　戯れにも厭いたわ
そろそろ姫に井戸に入ってもらおう
It's time for the princess to enter the Well.
Miss, we're almost to the gate.
お付の方　もう少しで門です
自分はこのままお付の方を負ぶって　江戸まで走って帰ります
I'll carry you all the way to Edo...
真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura!
姫　座興はしまいにしましょう
Princess, let us end this game.
お付の方はこちらに
Stay behind me, miss.
この期に及んで　姫を守るという忠義
Your loyalty in protecting
the princess, even now...
ネズミのくせに　褒めてやろう
Rat, you have my compliments.
It isn't loyalty!
忠義ではない
姫であろうとなかろうと
Whether she's a princess or not,
I shall protect her life.
命を守る　それは武士の務め
As a samurai, that is my duty!
Then fulfill it.
ではしっかり務めるがいい
Yukimura...
幸村　これが武士の務め
This is the duty of a samurai.
月島
Tsukishima!
よほどそのネズミがお気に入りのようですな
You appear to have quite
an interest in that rat.
拙者が存じ上げていた奈阿姫は　そのようなお方ではなかった
The Princess Naa I knew was very different.
How sad.
嘆かわしいや
You were such a kind girl, you would pity
あなたは一匹の醜い蟲さえ可愛がる　心優しい方だった
even an ugly insect.
But for you to take interest in such a rat...
だが　こんなネズミに目をかけるとは
このネズミ　先に殺しますかな
Perhaps I shall kill him first.
それとも姫が井戸に入られますか
Or will you enter the Well?
Miss, I won't die here!
お付の方　自分は死んでも死にません
おう　口だけは一人前だな
Oh?
If nothing else, you have a big mouth...
Stop!
やめよ
お付の方　なりません
No, miss...
Stop it, Yukimura!
やめよ　幸村
Please, stop this...
もう　やめよ
Lotus Root Blast!
蓮根玉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
末吉　為吉
これでしまい
This is the end.
小鳥さん
Kotori-san!
新手か
Reinforcements?
After you left, I did some thinking.
君達が旅立ってから　考えたんだ
もしも真田幸村が　蟲奉行様を手にかけるつもりだったら
If Sanada Yukimura had intended
to kill the Insect Magistrate,
真田十傑蟲で江戸を襲わせるはずだって
he would have attacked Edo with
the Ten Crucifix Insects.
そうなったら　僕達はなす術がなかった
Then there'd have been nothing for us to do.
なのに　幸村は猿飛佐助だけを差し向けた
But Yukimura sent only Sarutobi Sasuke.
これは何かあると思ったんだ
I thought there must have been a reason.
何を企む　蟲人よ
What are you planning, Insect-men?
知りませんね
I couldn't tell you!
我ら十傑蟲は 親方幸村様のお言葉に従うのみ
The Ten Crucifix Insects simply
obey our lord, Yukimura-sama.
親方様の深いお考えなど　拙者らには分からんわ
His deeper thoughts are beyond us.
やれやれ　とんだ小者だったようだ
My, my...
Then you're merely foot soldiers.
I'll show you what happened to the last person
我らを小者呼ばわりするお前達の末路　教えてあげますよ
who looked down on us.
そいつは大岡さんの…
Those are Oooka-san's...
Did you kill him?
君がやったのかい
その方はふそうにも　幸村様のお手を煩わせたようですね
Apparently, he was
disrespectful enough to challenge
Yukimura-sama directly.
そうだろうね
I'm sure he was...
君に大岡君を斬るのは無理だ
You could not have killed Oooka-kun.
火鉢君達は　蟲奉行様のところへ
All of you, go to the Magistrate.
What about you?
あんたはどうすんだ
この人達に 弟弟子を殺された兄弟子の怒りを
I must demonstrate to them the anger of one
whose fellow student
見せてあげなければ…なりません
has been killed.
さぁ　姫
Now, Princess...
私は無理強いするのはいやでございます
I dislike the idea of forcing you.
ご自身の思い通りになさいませ
Do as you wish.
分かった
All right.
しかし　その者の命は助けると約束せよ
But promise me you will not kill him.
承知　ですがこの命いつまで持ちますことか
Very well.
But how long will he live, either way?
おやめください
Please don't...
この者が約束など守るはずがありません
He won't keep his promise...
Little rat.
小ネズミが
わらわはお前のことを忘れてしまう
I will forget you.
However, please remember me.
だが　お前は覚えていてくれ
I shall never forget!
絶対に忘れません
自分がお付の方のことを覚えていないなど　ありえません
It's impossible for me to forget you.
I cannot... I am a samurai!
自分は武士です　死んでもあなたのことは忘れません
Even in death, I shall remember you.
I promise!
絶対に
Yes.
うむ
Even in death, I shall not forget you, either.
わらわも死んでも忘れんぞ　お前のことは
Miss...
お付の…
お付の方
Miss!
もはやお前達人の世ではないわ
The world no longer belongs to you humans.
蟲人の世になるんですよ
It will belong to the Insect-men.
つくづくつまらぬ小者ですね
You are of no importance.
何を
What?!
You little...
花鳥風流居合い
Flowering Wind-style Draw:
Divine Punishment.
天罰
なぜだ
Why?
なぜ黒揚羽にならぬ
Why does she not transform
into a Kuroageha butterfly?
常世の蟲の力を得た今
With the power of the Eternal Well,
you should become a Kuroageha butterfly...
あなたは黒揚羽になるはず
否　ならねばならん
No, you must!
枝垂桜
Flowering Branches!
末吉　為吉
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
Full-Power Corkscrew Punch!
全力コックスクリューパンチ
慈合い斬り
Compassion Slash!
花鳥風流居合い　飛燕返し
Flowering Wind-style Draw:
Flying Swallow!
み　皆さん
Everyone...
He's coming.
来るぞ
I'll have to take the princess
to Oosaka Castle by force.
こうなれば　無理やりにでも姫を大阪城へお連れする
The Insect Magistrate's will protect the servant!
お付の方は　蟲奉行所の面々が守る
貴様には負けあるのみ
You cannot win this!
そんな…
No...
Next Time
I'll never forget it!
自分は絶対忘れません
The warmth I felt in my hand...
この手が触れたぬくもりを
月島
Tsukishima...
The size of Oharu-dono's big peaches
この手が触れた お春殿の大きさも柔らかさも
or their softness!
結局それかい
That's how we're ending this?!
次回　蟲奉行「月島仁兵衛　ここにあり！！！」
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
Tsukishima Jinbei Is Here!!!
Tsukishima Jinbei Is Here.